Welcome to Dealmakers. I'm Sarah Sharp.
I'm a deal attorney who helps people buy
and sell businesses every day. And I'm
going to tell you the number one best
business to buy in 2025. And if you know
me at all, you already know what I'm
about to say. So, you can just skip this
and go to the next videos. Uh, the best
business to buy in 2025 is Wait, I guess
I should say before I get into it, if
you find this valuable, please like and
subscribe. If you're new to this
channel, it really helps us out. Um, and
while you're at it, check out
dealacademy.org. or if you're interested
in putting together a compelling offer
on a business, we have courses that will
show you all of that and give you some
uh direction. So, you might be thinking,
I'm saying that the best businesses to
buy in 2025 are going to be a laundromat
or a car wash or if you know me on a
personal level, I've probably told you
that I really want to invest in boat
storage. I think it sounds like a great
business model. Um, but the one hottest
business to buy in 2025 is bookkeeping.
It's an accounting practice. I see a ton
of people interested in it. It's
recessionp proof. And even the worst
case scenario uh that we see on a
political stage, whatever that might be,
like a for a tax practice, right,
they're all worried about having a flat
tax. But somebody still has to figure
out what to put the flat tax on. And the
definition of what that income is going
to be, you know, is going to be like a
hard one very argued descriptive
question. And these accounting practices
are no matter what change comes down the
pike, they do better. Also, have you
ever tried to find a new bookkeeper or
accountant? Because the way that I can
tell anyone goes about trying to find
one is they contact anyone they know in
the space and then that person says,
"Let me check to see if my person is
accepting new clients." And then half
the time says that, "I'm sorry, they're
not accepting new clients." When does
that ever happen in any other industry,
but that's how high the demand is and
how low the ability to meet the demand
is? That's how high the demand is. So
fantastic industry to invest in. The
other reason is because the multiples
you have the ability to get a finance.
The SBA program whenever it came out the
way that it works is the government said
to a lot of banks, this is a highle
version, but the government basically
said to a lot of banks, we're going to
create the small business administration
and we're going to back these somewhat
risky loans as long as you make them for
people to buy and sell small businesses.
So right now it's below 5 million in
purchase price and it's for primarily
full 100% buyouts of a company
primarily. So if that's what you're
trying to do, you can go to a lot of
different banks and they will actually
loan you up to 100% of the amount of the
money it takes for you to buy that
business. That is super impactful in the
accounting industry because it used to
be that before that everything was
seller financed over the course of many
many years. But that turned everything
on its head and made it so that banks
that historically would not have felt
comfortable lending against such a weird
asset. I say it's a weird asset because
it's not got warehouse full of widgets.
So there's nothing you can go repossess
if it turns out that you know the the
loan goes bad. It's just a client list
and goodwill. It's very mushy. you know,
what does that even mean? It's certainly
not something that a bank wants to go
take and try to make money out of. So,
there's basically no collateral that's
really, you know, there limited
collateral backing these loans. Most
banks absent the SBA program would not
make a loan against promises of future
cash flow. That's too nebulous. So, and
they certainly wouldn't loan 100% of the
buyout on promises of future collateral.
But SBA program says, "Hey, we're going
to back a great portion, the vast
majority of the amount that you loan
under this program as long as you follow
our rules called SOPs. Then if there's a
default, we insure it." Like the FDI
thing after the Great Depression. I'm
pretty sure. I haven't researched my
history in a long time, but I'm pretty
sure that's what the FDI started doing
is insuring, you know, a million dollars
of each like bank account because they
didn't want the Great Depression, the
run on banks to happen again. Similarly,
the SBA insures these loans. So because
of that, you can go and you can get a 7A
loan. You can get to 100% in certain
circumstances of the loan amount from
the bank that you need to buy one of
these accounting practices. So another
part and the reason at the beginning if
you noticed I said that the best
business to buy in 2025 was bookkeeping,
not accounting, is a lot of people don't
realize that there's, you know, this big
umbrella of different types of
accounting. There's audit and a test,
which you usually need a CPA license to
be able to do. That's over here. It's
typically projectbased. It's very
skilled labor. There's tax practice. The
fun thing about a pure tax practice if
you're looking to buy one is it really
matters when you're buying it in the
calendar year, right? Because if you're
buying it right after they made 100% of
their revenue for the year at the end of
a tax season, then you better be
prepared to float the working capital
for like eight or nine months until
you're at the next tax season. But you
can't buy them in the middle of tax
season because everyone's too busy. So
you really have a narrow range if it's a
tax practice to buy. Bookkeeping,
however, is hard to find in a standalone
capacity. But if you can find a pure
bookkeeping practice, often they have
monthly recurring revenue. So everyone
is called MRR and their clients are
signed up, you know, to pay a certain
amount every month to make sure that
their books are reconciled. And usually
is strictly speaking like only
bookkeeping firm is not doing the tax
prep. It's certainly not doing audit and
a test. So it doesn't need somebody who
is a CPA or an EA or anything like that
to be running it. Just regular folks can
buy a bookkeeping practice as long as
they're not doing that other stuff. So
that opens up a lot of different buyers.
And if you're going to buy it to grow it
and sell it, you're going to be able to
take advantage of the fact that you've
got a lot of different buyers on the
back end. Another reason is that monthly
recurring revenue is very rare. Most tax
practices certainly audit audit and
attest and most businesses generally
outside of accounting are unpredictable.
I mean, but yet bookkeeping with their
monthly recurring revenue really starts
to look more like a typical SAS deal and
software as a service where you can
predict and and really project out
saying, "Okay, well, if we have average
of 5% attrition on our client base
year-over-year, but we have this many
people signed up, you know, we predict
with pretty good levels of accuracy what
we're going to make next year." And that
is so powerful and so rare in the
context of something like professional
services. The other reason why
bookkeeping is the best business to buy
in 2025 is because the profit margin can
be really big. If it's not in the
business you're looking at, you already
know just by looking at it how to
increase the profit margin. And pretty
much anybody who even knew what MBA
stood for could figure out how to
increase the profit margin. I mean
people, there's lots of great qualified
offshore labor. There's lots of AI
solutions. There are so many ways and
the market really bears an increase in
rates often. And most people are moving
remote. So there's a lot of really low
hanging fruit or lowhanging levers you
can pull to increase the profit margin
of a bookkeeping practice right away.
And so you can buy a million-doll
practice that's making
$300,000 a year and by the end of the
first year have it making 500 without
even bringing in new clients. And that's
a regular that's a regular change. So
then you're paying on a loan for, you
know, something that you've already
improved and are reaping the benefits
of. So for all of these reasons, uh
bookkeeping practice, the prevalence of
7A loan buyouts, absolutely the best
practice, the best industry, the best
business to buy in 2025. just good luck
finding one because they're not that
common and the people who do like
bookkeeping are hanging on to it because
it's a great deal. It's um it can be a
real lifestyle business and for the
final reason that people love scooping
up bookkeeping businesses in 2025 is
because they complement everything else
that you're doing as an entrepreneur.
And that is, I think, the real final bow
tying it together is if you are looking
at several different investments or if
you're like me and you've got several
companies that you run, it can be really
powerful to have a bookkeeping company
to keep all your books straight because
I pay a ton of money to sort through all
the books and make sure that I'm
prepared for each tax season. If I could
bring that in-house, you better believe
I would. And at the end of this video, I
just talked myself into trying to buy a
bookkeeping firm. So if you feel the
same, please like and subscribe, visit
Deal Academy, and have a great